<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Fatima Kahil</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/</link><description>This is a demo site for Nikola.</description><atom:link href="https://fakahil.github.io/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:fakahil92@gmail.com"&gt;Fatima Kahil&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 16:18:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Distractions and balance</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/jumping-between-projects/index.html</link><dc:creator>Fatima Kahil</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally, everything in life is fine as long as my work is going on track, meaning if I am getting the wanted result from my current task. That is why when things don't go the way I expect in one project, I get busy with another mental task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our minds need constant change, I cannot be focused on one task for more than one week. That is why I am writing this blog actually. This is how I like to distract myself from work: learning a programming language, a new computing skill. For me, the thrill of learning something new and applying it myself is a major help to proceed with stuck ideas in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to feel guilty whenever perform a non-work related task, thinking that I should be reading a paper instead, but everything you do and learn will eventually help you with your professional project, if not, it will get your mind off your task, refresh it so you could get back with a new perspective. It is good sometimes to take some distance (not only in human relationships;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/jumping-between-projects/index.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 16:21:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to do Research</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/how-to-do-research/index.html</link><dc:creator>Fatima Kahil</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I mean by research is all the steps you need to do when working on a specific project, meaning that you have a question which you're trying to answer using the resources available to you. So a typical homework is not considered as research. A homework is a set of problems which you are supposed to solve after learning about a certain scientific topic at school. This is not research, because you already know which topic this problem belongs to, it's enough to study that specific topic, or if you are an A-student, you could go beyond the points covered in class in your free time. But in any case, you know exactly what to look for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing research for the first time is bumpy. You have no idea how to start, which points you should be focusing on, and which material you should use, and most importantly, how to finish on time. Research in Astronomy is the art of knowing which areas of Math or Physics you should be revising or learning for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, you need some time before mastering research techniques, and eventually scientific writing. But that's another topic. Let's stick here to doing research the "right" way, focusing on the field of Physics and Astronomy.
First, you have to know which resources are accessible to you in your institution or place of work: data, software, labs..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, what tools should you be using to analyze and process your data. I would suppose that you speak at least one programming language, my favorite is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, it is becoming widely used within the Astronomical society, especially among young junior researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, how to approach the problem. Well, first you have to read a bit about the topic, but here is where you probably need help. If you are a perfectionist like me, you would have the urge to know everything about the topic before jumping into the analysis, you would be tempted to know the whole theory thinking that this can help converge faster to the solution of your problem. I used to do that, but it is time consuming, and it will most probably leave you frustrated after knowing that you just cannot embrace all the theory in the time frame given to you. I would recommend doing the following: just read randomly about the topic in different journals or books or even dissertations. Don't read in a structured way, you have to collect the "broad knowledge" and especially what approaches others do to tackle it. Then little by little you target specific points and focus on specific ideas, of course you should be checking your data and doing some analysis tests along the way. You want to find the right questions, and that depends on the data you have in hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, my current post doc position is directed more towards image processing and optical engineering than doing basic science. I am analyzing calibration data for a space mission which promises new era of Solar Physics Research. And for those interested in the data products of such missions, images need to be cleaned up for any optical imperfection.
(Side-note: I find this kind of research more appealing, since it is predefined what you have to get: people might be relying on you to find the platescale of an image or the modulation transfer function of the telescope for example, there are no open questions or gazillion theory on how to do it, it is straightforward, you have to get a number at the end and there are no speculation about it, it is either the right or the wrong number).
Anyway, since there is little resources on image processing in Astrophysics (except for those working in Astrometry), I am reading publications in medical imaging and industrial machine vision journals. And that is totally O.K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are doing research in a new topic, or you have a new method that you are trying to learn, be it in image processing, or coding, or just a theoretical idea that is essential to understand to carry on with your analysis, you will find yourself unfamiliar with a lot of scientific principles, and to understand something you have to go back a million steps (what people call wikipedia black hole). But thinking about the problem every day and consistently researching it will help you clear any difficulty. Once you experiment enough with your data and keep reading, you will find yourself comfortable with any complication that might arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don't forget to discuss with others, no matter at which stage your research is. When I first started my PhD I considered asking questions a sign of ignorance and laziness, well of course it is if done more than necessary, after all the point of being a researcher is doing it yourself! but discussing will save a lot of time and frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss with your colleagues or your supervisor, or the researchers in your group. When you talk about your problem out loud and explain it to others, not only it shows how well you understand your problem, but you could get different perspectives, get asked questions which might direct you to the right way. It often happens that we are focused on solving a complication following a certain line of reasoning and unable to think of it from different perspectives. Discuss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/how-to-do-research/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:43:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to PhD</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/how-to-phd/index.html</link><dc:creator>Fatima Kahil</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is definitely not an easy post to write. Here I am writing it a year after my defense and six months into my first postdoc position. Jumping into a PhD does not come with a manual, and I've learned (the hard way) that there is no ONE way to do it, it is an art rather than a well defined procedure. However, there are usually a few relevant questions you should be considering before starting a PhD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do some history research: What was/is expected in Academia from a PhD student and what is the original idea of getting a doctorate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do you want to get a PhD degree?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can a PhD degree serve your future career (I think the answer to this question becomes clearer in the late stages of your PhD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just an introduction to those who just found this blog and want to pursue a career in Academia, or they are already at it. There will be more elaborate posts on handling the different parts of a PhD/postdoc research and of an academic life in general. I should note here that this is my personal experience and you might or might not find it useful to follow the same mentality and/or practice. Everyone's experience is different, we have different reasons and different journeys that led us to where we are, and the way we approach situations is linked to a large extent to our social, ethnic and political background.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>academia</category><category>phd</category><category>research</category><guid>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/how-to-phd/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 17:29:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>