<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Fatima Kahil (Posts about phd)</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://fakahil.github.io/categories/phd.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:fakahil92@gmail.com"&gt;Fatima Kahil&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 16:11:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How to PhD</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/how-to-phd/index.html</link><dc:creator>Fatima Kahil</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is definitely not an easy post to write. Here I am writing it a year after my defense and six months into my first postdoc position. Jumping into a PhD does not come with a manual, and I've learned (the hard way) that there is no ONE way to do it, it is an art rather than a well defined procedure. However, there are usually a few relevant questions you should be considering before starting a PhD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do some history research: What was/is expected in Academia from a PhD student and what is the original idea of getting a doctorate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do you want to get a PhD degree?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can a PhD degree serve your future career (I think the answer to this question becomes clearer in the late stages of your PhD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just an introduction to those who just found this blog and want to pursue a career in Academia, or they are already at it. There will be more elaborate posts on handling the different parts of a PhD/postdoc research and of an academic life in general. I should note here that this is my personal experience and you might or might not find it useful to follow the same mentality and/or practice. Everyone's experience is different, we have different reasons and different journeys that led us to where we are, and the way we approach situations is linked to a large extent to our social, ethnic and political background.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>academia</category><category>phd</category><category>research</category><guid>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/how-to-phd/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 17:29:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>