<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Fatima Kahil (Posts about work)</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://fakahil.github.io/categories/work.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:fakahil92@gmail.com"&gt;Fatima Kahil&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 14:54:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>On learning German - Part 1</title><link>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/on-learning-german-p1/index.html</link><dc:creator>Fatima Kahil</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My experience with the German language cannot fit into this post, I will for sure get back to this topic again. I honestly did not care much about learning it when I first arrived to Germany. I was fixated on one goal: getting my PhD. My life was revolving around this objective and everything else was not that important, was not seen, exactly like in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/06/books/review/Bloom-t.html"&gt;Invisible Gorilla psychological experiment&lt;/a&gt;. I was busy counting ball passes and missing the walking Gorilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is often how I approached daily things, as an expatiate with identity issues, I've always considered myself a temporary resident, and I am not to blame, it was all around me: every year I have to renew my residence permit, I am always reminded that if I don't have a job, if this country does not need me, then I'm out. Period. In addition, back then I did not speak the language, I couldn't understand anything, be it on the streets, in the supermarkets, on the bus. So I've always had this idea that I am passing through, for 4 years. I obviously underestimated time. I did not buy big things because well I had no idea where the future would take me, especially that I am a light packer so I did not want to worry about carrying my belongings anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was about time to change this mentality. I should buy a TV, and I should speak the language. Life should not revolve about work only (a reminder to myself :P), it takes a big part of it true (it is the reason I got here in the first place) but we are humans after all, we need to take other "human" things into consideration. And I am not not talking about having hobbies, I am not a workaholic with no other interests, but the feeling of guilt upon exercising them was the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've decided to learn German. I knew that learning it will not just help me with my future career, it will grant me access to know about this country's history and culture. Without it I will not be able to know what's around me, what interests Germans: the topics they discuss, the books they write, how they think, behave, approach situations, it is an integral key if I want to live among them and interact with them on a daily basis. So before deciding to embark on this endeavor, I have also made the decision to stay in Germany, at any cost. At least if I have this variable fixed then I'd be more motivated to focus on the language learning process. Yes life is a model with so many damned variables, and reducing the number of variables will make it converge faster to the optimum solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the 28th of December 2018, the night I got back to Goettingen from my second trip to my home country (yes I did not spend new year there), I opened the A1.1 textbook that I've bought a year before and never used, and on that night, the ship has sailed (after I got on board so nothing is missed and it's the right idiom to use here, thank you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only with time that I've realized it was actually no separate journey to learn this magnificent language, it was integrated in every aspect of my everyday life, but only when I FOCUSED on that Gorilla that I was able to see it, and throw the ball at its face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>expat</category><category>focus</category><category>german</category><category>work</category><guid>https://fakahil.github.io/posts/on-learning-german-p1/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 12:40:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>